Western mining documents, maps, and photographs M2157
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Western mining documents, maps, and photographs
c. 1900-1941
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Marc Selvaggio, Bookseller ABAA
M2157
1.06 Linear Feet (1 manuscript box and 1 flat box)
Content Description
Materials include a variety of documents related to mining operations (primarily in California and Nevada, though with some documents related to Colorado and British Columbia), including plans, printed matter, reports on properties, agreements, financials, maps, several reports on tungsten, blueprints, photographs, and negatives.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was purchased by Stanford University, Special Collections in September 2016.
Arrangement
Arranged by material type.
Mines and mineral resources -- California; Tungsten mines and mining; Mines and mineral resources -- Nevada
- Reports on properties, development and water system for Tulameen River, [British Colombia] (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Survey of Flume Line for Sootheran Property; Cover letter from R.K. Brown to John Heizer, November 1936 relating to dredging and hydraulic propositions (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Calaveras Copper Company [California], Plan and Agreement, September 15, 1929 and numerous other reports and documents pertaining to it (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
- Oneida Gold Mining and Milling Company Sixth Annual Statement, and Superintendent's Report for the year ending August 31st, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Report on the Property of the South Jackson Mining Company Jackson, Amador County, Cal, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Report on the Mining Property of the LeClaire Consolidated Mines Company, Colorado Springs, 1933; Mary McKinney-Le Claire Gold Mine, Cripple Creek, Colorado, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The Story of Gold & Silver Circle Mines Inc. A Speculative Opportunity, 1935; Prospectus, Gold & Silver Circle Mines Inc., May 29, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- A general Survey of the Tungsten Situation, October 1, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mineral Abstracts: Tungsten, 1939; The World's Tungsten Reserves, 1937; Memorandum Concerning Tungsten Localities in California for Mr. Charles H. Segerstrom, January 1938 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Maps: a portion of Mohave County Arizona; gold bearing veins of the Soulsbyville district; cross section of Davidson shaft; cross section of of Central shaft, 8.5 x 11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Photographs: miscellaneous prints (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Negatives (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Photographs - California: Bunker Hill mine, Amador; Carson Hill mine; Melones Lake, Stanislaus River; Columbia street scene ca. 1930's; small mining towns in Northern California ca 1930's; 7" x 17" black and white panoramic (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
- Photographs - Nevada: Golconda plant; Pacific Tungsten mill, Humboldt County; Avalon; Nightingale Mine; mining operations and desert landscape views; employees of mining operations; 7 x 17 black and white panoramic; three aerial views of Golconda, Oreana, and Ragged Top, 9.25 x 9.25 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
- Negatives of panoramic prints (Flat-box 2)
- Properties of the California Exploration Co., Limited, Amador County, Cal, 1912. Blueprint (Map-folder 3)
- Plan of Alpine Mine, Amador County, Cal (ca. 1910). Blueprint (Map-folder 3)
- Argonaut Hoffman and Kennedy Ore Bodies. Vertical Longitudinal Section, N.Y. 1908. Blueprint (Map-folder 3)
- Plan of the Argonaut Mine, Amador County, Cal, March 1910. Blueprint (Map-folder 3)
- Longitudinal Section in Plane of Empire Lode, [1929?]. Two reverse blue print, one copy with added colors. Also shows Pacific Mine vein. (Map-folder 3)
- Plan of Underground Workings, South Empire Shaft at Plymouth, California. April 1941. Reverse blueprint, partially hand-colored, with added penciled notes 5/11/41 (Map-folder 3)
- Plat of Surface Lines and Portion of Underground Work of Pacific and Empire Mines, Plymouth, Amador County, California, compiled from surveys made by D. D. Reaves, 1880-1883, drawn 1911. Blueprint (Map-folder 3)
- Empire, Pacific and Indiana Mines. Large hand-drawn, annotated, hand-colored map on linen cloth (Map-folder 3)
- Lincoln Core (?) Sutter Creek, Cal, 1910. Two blueprints, one with red highlights of mines adjacent and near the Lincoln mine and the other shows the shaft, levels, slate lines, etc. of this mine (Map-folder 3)
- Lincoln Quartz MIne with five title sections (Map-folder 3)
- Plymouth Mine, Plymouth, Calif. 1400 ft. North Level, (ca 1900). Hand-drawn and hand-colored map on linen cloth, Damp stain and discoloration, cleaned for mold. (Map-folder 3)
- Section on Vein Through Rise at 910 ft. North, 1400 level to [?] ft, Plymouth Cons. Gold Mines Ltd., Plymouth, Calif (ca. 1900). Hand-drawn and hand-colored map on linen cloth (Map-folder 3)
- Section on Vein Through Winze at 910 ft North, 1400 level to [?], Plymouth Cons. Gold MInes Ltd., Plymouth, Calif. (ca 1900). Hand-drwan and hand-colored map on linen cloth (Map-folder 3)
- Diagrammatic Cross-Sections, Plymouth Mine (ca 1910). Reverse bluepriint (Map-folder 3)
- Oneida Mine Stope Map, 1906-1907, with note on verso: Jackson, CA 1911. Blueprint (Map-folder 3)
- Plan of the Oneida Mine Amador County, 1902. Reverse blueprint (Map-folder 3)